[All examinees who have finished checking]
所有看完成绩的考生
[your scores please come sign here,]
抓紧过来签字
[and get ready for the final exam.]
参加最后一门考试
[All examinees who have finished checking]
所有看完成绩的考生
[your scores please come sign here,]
抓紧时间过来签字
[and get ready for the final exam.]
参加最后一门考试
Xiang Yuansheng is amazing!
这向远生厉害了
He could get into the Police Department.
这成绩可以进总局了吧
-He can. -Definitely!
可以了 可以了
He will.
可以进总局了
[Really?]
真的
[He can surely be admitted.]
都可以直接进去了
[I'm as good as him.]
他也不差 我也不差
[All three of us have passed.]
咱三个都过了 其实
[All examinees who have finished checking]
看完成绩的考生
[your scores please come sign here,]
抓紧时间过来签字
[and get ready for the final exam.]
参加最后一门考试
[Come and sign your name here.]
抓紧过来签字
Sign your name.
向远生签字
Xiang Yuansheng!
向远生
Are you Xiang Yuansheng?
你就是向远生
Yes.
是
You are straight-A, buddy!
小伙子 你厉害
You got full scores
一共考了两门
on the two subject exams.
你两门全是满分
If you pass the last exam,
等会儿笔试好好考
I'm sure you will be
分配到总局
assigned to the Police Department.
肯定没问题啊
Can I make my own choice?
我只能分配到总局
If you get another high score on the exam,
照你这么考下去
you will top the list of all.
稳稳当当是第一名
You will be given a position
总局不会让你这种人才
in the Police Department.
到别的地方去
[Examinees]
所有前两项
[who have passed the two subject exams]
考试通过的人
Just go inside.
快去吧 快去吧
[should go in the exam room now]
抓紧时间进入考场
Go ahead
快去吧
[to prepare for the last written exam.]
准备最后一项笔试
[Examinees]
所有通过
[who have passed the two subject exams]
前两项考试的人
[should go in the exam room now]
抓紧时间进入考场
[to prepare for the last written exam.]
准备最后一项笔试
[Your final score is]
三科相加
[the sum of all your subject scores.]
才是总成绩
[Three minutes to go.]
还有三分钟就要考试了
[Get in the exam room as soon as possible.]
抓紧时间进入考场
Don't be late.
不要迟到
Brother,
哥
I have a friend from Shanghai.
我有个上海的朋友
He wants to join the police force.
想当警察
But he missed a subject exam
但他入职考核的时候
when he took the entrance examination.
错过了一门
So, he failed.
所以没有通过
I intend to help him serve as a police constable
我想帮他
in the Fourth Station House.
去第四所当警察
[The Fourth Station House?]
第四所
[It sounds mysterious.]
这么神秘
[I've never heard of it.]
我没听说过啊
Is it a secret service
是什么保密机构
or a special research institute?
和特殊研究所什么的吗
[It belongs to the Police Department.]
是在上海市公安局
OK.
公安局
It's not a problem.
总局没问题
[The Fourth Station House is affiliated]
总局下属的十六铺分局
to the Shiliupu Police Station which
再下属的
is again affiliated to the Police Department.
第四警察所
A station house?
警察所
I'm the secretary of the Office of Aides.
你让我一个侍从室秘书
You need me to get a position in a small station house?
往警察所托人
[I have an idea.]
要不然这样吧
I can buy him a train ticket
我给他买张票
to come to Nanjing.
让他来南京
I can offer him a position
我在首都警察厅
in the Metropolitan Police Agency.
给他安排一个位置
Do you agree?
你看行不行
[If he insists on staying in Shanghai,]
如果在上海的话
[at least, he should be given a position]
至少也是
[in the Police Department.]
上海市公安局
That is all I can do for now.
再往下我不认识人了
But he insisted on working in the Fourth Station House.
我朋友说他就想去四所
He said it is close to his house.
他说 离家近
[I don't understand.]
你这什么朋友啊
OK, I got it.
行行行 我知道了
What about you?
那你呢
Have you bought a ticket back to Nanjing?
回南京的票买了没有
I have some private business to deal with.
我还有点私事儿
I will come back after getting it done.
忙完了就回来
[Mom is missing you very much.]
妈妈想你了
[In a few days]
过几天
[two ladies from the Ministry of Finance]
财政部的两个太太
[will treat her to a meal.]
请她吃饭
[She wants you to join.]
想带你一起去
I will come back in a month at best.
最多不超过一个月
[A month?]
一个月
[You don't want to come back, do you?]
我看你是不想回来了吧
OK, I'll help.
行 我知道了
What is the name of your friend?
你那个朋友叫什么名字
His name is
他叫
Xiang Yuansheng.
向远生
[All the cadets]
所有通过
[who have passed the entrance exam]
入职考试的警员
[come here to fill in forms.]
现在过来填写资料
[All cadets will be assigned to]
所有警员
[relative departments by their final scores.]
需要按照成绩分配
Xiang Yuansheng,
向远生啊
What was wrong with you?
你怎么搞的
You performed great initially
前面两门功课考了一百
and got two full marks.
全都挺好的
And got a zero on the last subject exam.
最后一门考了个零分
You got a chance to the Police Department.
本来稳稳当当进总局
Now you have to work in a station house.
现在 去警察所
Which one?
请问 是哪个警察所
The Fourth Station House of the Shiliupu Police Station.
十六铺分局第四警察所
Sign your name.
报到 签字
Thank you.
谢谢
Nothing to thank for.
没什么好谢的
You will regret it.
到那里你会后悔的
Three, two, one.
三 二 一
Tianxiang,
天祥
bought your sister breakfast again?
又给你妹买早餐去了
Good morning, He.
早啊老贺
You got up so early today.
今天这么早啊
Uncle Zhao.
赵叔
Morning, Tianxiang.
天祥回来了
Good morning.
早
Aunt Mei.
梅婶
Hello, Tianxiang.
天祥回来了
Tianxiang,
天祥
Today is the first day for Minmin
你家珉敏
to serve in the station house.
今天不是去报到吗
But we didn't see her go.
怎么还没见她人呢
She is dressing up at home.
打扮呢
It is reasonable to dress up
女孩儿第一天报到
in the first day to work.
总得漂漂亮亮的
[Aunt Wang, two more fried bread sticks.]
王婶 再来两根油条
[Right away.]
好嘞
Dad, breakfast is ready.
爸 早饭我买回来了
Tell your sisters to make it quick.
让你妹妹她们快点儿
I will.
好嘞
Mr. Luo,
骆师傅
Can I get my photos
我那个照片
today?
今天能取吗
No problem.
没问题
Thank you.
好
[You always covet what others have.]
谁说别人有你就要有的
[Don't think about it.]
能不能学好
[I just want to try it on.]
你不能给我戴一下
[You are too young to wear it.]
你好好学习戴什么发卡
[This is too much.]
你现在胆子大了是吧
[How dare you hit me.]
还敢动手了
[All the girls in my class have hair clips.]
我们班同学都有发卡
[I will wear it today.]
我今天就要戴
Stop it.
干什么
I'll kick your ass.
看我今天不打你
You dare to try me.
你敢动手 你
I won't give it to you.
不可能给你
It is mine.
这是我的
I bought it.
我的钱买的
Brother, she is bullying me.
哥 你看她不讲理
It's mine.
就是我的
[Listen to me.]
我跟你说
[I bought it.]
我买的
[Luo Qinqin,]
骆勤芹
Come down for breakfast when it is over.
打一会儿就下楼吃饭啊
[No way.]
就不
[Luo Minmin,]
骆珉敏
[Stop flattering yourself]
我劝你别臭美了
[A hair clip can't make you more attractive.]
戴了发卡也没有我好看
I'm showing off
长得好看的人
because I look pretty.
才有资格臭美呢
But you don't.
不像有的人
So you have nothing to flatter about.
连臭美的资格都没有
I'm so blessed
老天爷还是偏爱我呀
to join the police force.
让我当上了警察
Luo Qinqin,
骆勤芹
the hair clip on my hair
我别这个卡子
makes me look more gorgeous.
真的特别好看
Do you want to admire that?
你要不要过来看一眼
I will not.
我才不看呢
What a narcissist!
神经病
I'm not.
说谁神经病呢
Come back here.
你给我回来
Button up the collar.
这小扣子一扣
Then
就两个字
my charisma is hard to hide.
气质
Luo Minmin.
骆珉敏
I thought you had given up
我以为两年没考上
after two-year consecutive exam failures.
你都该放弃了呢
I didn't expect
没想到这都第三年了
you should pass the exam this year.
竟然让你给考上了
Brother, the enrollment
哥 今年一共就招
is limited to 98 persons.
九十八个警员
She ranks the last on the admission list.
她就考第九十八名
Not a single point
你想要多一分
more.
她都没有
It is useless to get more scores.
多一分也没有用啊
After all, I'm in a police uniform now.
我穿上警服就是胜利
When you were born,
人出生的时候
if God had a scale,
要是有杆天平
he must have put more weights
老天爷一定是
on your luck
把该给你脑子的砝码
than your wisdom.
都给了运气
I'd love to accept it.
那也没少给我呀
What can you do about it?
怎么样
I'm a lucky girl.
我就是幸运
God always likes me.
老天爷就是喜欢我
That is not true.
老天爷哪喜欢你了
You are dumb
这么笨
and couldn't pass any exams.
考什么都考不及格
You didn't learn anything.
什么东西都不会
So stop fancying yourself.
你有什么好嚣张的
Hell, it is true.
我就是嚣张怎么了
You are good at anything,
你看看你行不行
except sports.
体育就是不行
That's enough.
行了
If blessed by God,
要是运气好
she shouldn't pass the exam.
就不该考上
In case a war broke out,
这万一打起仗来
you would be drawn to the front line.
你就不怕被拉去挡枪啊
Dad.
爸
I serve in a station house.
我去的可是警察所
I won't have a chance to fight a war.
想受伤都没机会的那种
We are running
那家里这么大的
such a big shop.
一个铺子
Somebody must take responsibility for it.
总得有人管吧
Look,
你看看
I'm the backbone of our family.
咱爸多需要我呀
Dad,
爸爸
my brother can help you.
这不是还有哥哥呢吗
I'd thank god if he handled himself well.
他能管好自己就不错了
If you decide to serve in the police force,
你要当警察啊
I have a request.
我有一个要求
When confronting with something dangerous,
遇到了危险
you mustn't be the first one to charge ahead.
不能第一个往前冲
Stay away from any harm if you can.
能躲就躲
If you can't,
实在躲不过
just run.
拔腿就跑
Do you get what I said?
你听见吗
Promise me.
你别敷衍我
Dad.
爸
Don't worry about me.
放心吧
I will protect myself.
我会保护好自己的
[Are we in the right place?]
咱这是不是来错地方了
[No one is here except us.]
怎么一个人都没有啊
[Just wait here.]
那就等着呗
[The officer is not coming yet.]
来 长官没来
This is my business card.
咱们先看一下
Nice to meet you.
你好 你好 你好
Take it, please.
来 看一下 看一下
I'm Sun Hongfa.
鄙人孙鸿发
The Hongfa Restaurant,
鸿发酒楼
just as my name implies,
这顾名思义啊
is run by my family.
是我们家开的
From now on,
即日起呢
all of you
在座的各位
and I are colleagues,
那就都是 都是同僚了
which means we are friends
是同僚 那就是朋友
and brothers
是朋友 那就是兄弟
and sisters.
还有个姐妹
If you come to my restaurant for dinner,
以后来我们家酒楼吃饭
just mention my name
别的不说
to its manager.
提我名字
You will be given a discount.
打个折是没有问题
Officer Sun,
孙警官
is your family
那你们家条件
very rich?
是不是特别好啊
Not so much.
一般 一般
My family and I
也就是
merely want for nothing
衣食无忧
That's all.
罢了 罢了
God damn it.
你说这一天天的啊
This abduction case
这诱拐案
can be broken.
它就是个烂摊子
As soon as the superior assigned the case,
上头一说
our inspector took it over.
所长就答应了
He's never even thought about us.
他什么时候想过我们
The inspector did take over the case.
案子是所长接的
But the captain put the most time
但白天跑得最多
and effort into the case.
晚上熬夜最多的是队长
He didn't complain about it.
队长都没埋怨呢
Why are you feeling aggrieved?
你埋怨什么
It's not what I mean.
我也不是埋怨
We all know
你说 这个案子
the captain should be credited
从头到尾
for the investigation of the case.
都是队长闷头查的
Unexpectedly,
结果出风头的
the inspector pushed himself forward.
就是他所长一个人
In my opinion,
我觉得队长
the captain is a little bit silly.
他就是有点儿傻
Shut up.
你说谁傻呢
I know the captain treats us well.
我知道队长对我们好
If he was not here,
要不是因为队长
I would have left the station house
我也不可能
years ago.
从四所坚持到现在
But I have to feed my family.
可是我也得养家糊口啊
Right?
是吧
Take the checking of household registration,
我们出去查个户口
we couldn't
人家给个苹果
accept nothing from householders.
都得还回去
It would never happen
你说有哪个警察所
in any other station houses.
是这样的
If he insists on doing this,
再这样下去
I'll quit.
真是没法干了
Get out of here if you want to give it up.
想干干 不想干滚蛋
I'm not targeting you.
不是 我又没说你
What the hell are you yelling at?
你嚷嚷什么
I knew clearly
别以为我不知道
what you thought.
你那些心思
You attempted to
你想让你弟弟
let your brother wear the police uniform.
进来当警察
But he was kicked out
结果让这帮新瓜蛋子
by these raw recruits.
给顶了
I feel embarrassed for you.
我都替你觉得丢脸
Don't you dare to say it again?
再说一遍
Shame on you!
我再说一遍怎么了
Shut up!
叫你说
[Stop fighting. We are colleagues.]
别动手 都是战友
Let go!
放开
Li.
大李 大李
Don't fight.
吵两句就行了
Stop it.
怎么还打起来了
That's enough.
放开 放开
Li.
大李 大李
Li, stop it.
大李 别打了
Let go.
别打了
Damn you.
去你的
Li, stop it.
大李 别
Bai.
老白 老白
Move away.
起开
I'm done
这活 我没法干了
and I quit.
谁爱干谁干
So do I, Bai.
我也不干了 老白
Tell the captain I'm sorry.
石头对不住队长了
Wait for me, Li.
大李 等等我
You have made yourself stand out.
发达喽
I'm feeling so happy
看着你发达啊
for you.
我也跟着开心
I won't go there.
我不去
My aspiration is to serve as a policeman.
我没想过不当警察
Nonsense.
又说气话
Mr. Jin
金老板
is a tycoon.
大老板
He is a rich man.
有的是钱
If you do the personal bodyguard for him,
给人家做私人保镖
your salary a month would be
一个月的薪水
worth that of half a year in a station house.
够你在警察所干半年的
You helped him to break a case.
要不是你给人破了案
That's why you're offered such a good job.
人家才懒得帮你呢
Cherish this opportunity.
珍惜机会
They offer me a job.
那人家请我
Why do you go with me?
你去干吗呀
You know why.
这还用问啊
You always
就你
pull a long face
黑着个脸
and have no talking skills.
不会说话
Just stand there
往那儿一站
like a statue.
跟榆木疙瘩似的
You need my help there.
我不得去帮你啊
No.
我不去
Today is the day for new recruits.
今天四所来新人
As an inspector, you should greet them.
你一所长 你就不管啊
Just a bunch of inferior students.
歪瓜裂枣的
Let them wait there.
让他们等着去吧
Think about it.
我还没说这事儿呢
Out of a total of 98 cadets admitted,
全市一共招九十八个人
we got those at the bottom of the list, again.
结果又是最后几名
If only we could get
好歹分一个前九十的
those of top 90.
给我们呀
I heard
听说还有一个
one of them didn't even get through
是走后门的
the admission line but still was admitted.
连录取线都不过
Guess what,
你还别说啊
maybe this back-door student has
没准就这个走后门的
some true skills and genuine knowledge.
还有点儿真才实学
I was told that
我可听说啊
he got full scores
三门考试
in two subject exams
两门满分
but missed the last one in the end.
有一门是缺考了
Otherwise,
要不然啊
he would get through the admission line.
也不会不够及格线的
The streetcar is coming.
车来了
I'm not going.
我不去
You have to.
听话
Easy, easy.
告诉你 不许这样
Let's go.
听话听话 走走走
Zuo.
老左
Get in.
走了 走了
"Carp jumps over the dragon gate"
鲤鱼跳龙门喽
If he is like what you said,
真有这能力啊
he didn't need somebody to back-door him.
还用走后门啊
I reckon his scores are fake.
我估计连成绩都是假的
What's his name?
他叫什么名字啊
I don't care his name.
管 管他叫什么名字
Listen up.
我告诉你啊
Now we are on the way
咱们去的是
to a French high-class restaurant.
法国高级餐厅
Take care of your appearance and behavior.
注意你的仪容仪表
If you were appreciated someday,
你发达了
that would be my honor.
我不也跟着享福吗
Got it.
知道
Look at the girl by that door.
你看那车门口
She is really pretty.
那女孩儿长得多漂亮
Which one?
哪个
The one in the front.
前面那个
Well...
还
You are 29 years old.
二十九了
You are not a child.
还像个孩子
Excuse me.
你好
I want to put up a missing person notice.
我想登个寻人启事
Come over.
寻人启事这边
What do you want to post?
什么内容
Here.
在这儿
You want to find your teacher?
寻恩师啊
[I wish all bridges]
愿你桥都坚固
[and all tunnels your pass be firm and bright.]
隧道都光明
From whom?
落款呢
No name.
不用了
You don't leave a name on it.
你这不留姓名
How should he know you are after him?
人家哪知道你在找他呀
He will.
会知道的
Thank you.
谢谢
Chen Hao.
陈浩
Where are you?
臭小子回来了没有
Come out.
陈浩出来
Stop it.
别喊了
He didn't come back.
队长没回来
What's wrong with you?
你又怎么了
You are looking upset.
愁眉苦脸的
Li and Shitou quitted.
大李跟石头不干了
What can I say?
不干不干吧
They would quit anyway.
该走的留不下
We need fresh blood.
旧的不去 新的不来嘛
You got married in this suit?
你结婚去了 穿这身
Line up.
列队
Attention!
立正
Let me introduce
给大家介绍一下啊
this man standing in front of you.
你们面前的这位
He is the police inspector
就是我们
of the Fourth Station House
上海市公安局
of the Shiliupu Police Station
十六铺分局下属的
of the Police Department.
福乐路第四警察所所长
Zuo Ronghua.
左荣华
You may clap.
可以鼓掌了
At ease.
大家不要拘谨啊
We can be like a family.
都是一家人
From now on,
以后呢
just call me Zuo.
就叫我老左就可以了
The station house has a bad reputation.
都说我们四所不好
But I don't think so.
我却不以为然
I can feel its warmth.
我觉着四所很温暖
Just like a big family.
就像一个大家庭
Hence,
所以我希望各位同僚
I hope everyone of you
也能够
will make the station house
把四所当成自己的
your another big family.
另一个家
I think
新来的警员呢
it's better to introduce yourself first.
都先做一下自我介绍
Talk about why you want to be a policeman.
说一说为什么要当警察
Who will be the first?
谁先说
I will.
我 我
OK.
好
Sir,
报告所长
my name is Sun Hongfa.
我叫孙鸿发
My father is the owner
我爸爸是
of the Hongfa Restaurant.
鸿发酒楼的老板
My uncle
我舅舅跟
and Chief Wang of the Fifth Baojia District
第五保的王保长
are sworn brothers.
是结拜兄弟
This is my family's business card.
自己家买卖
Here you are.
来
Good.
好 好 好
My family wanted me
本来家里安排我
to serve in government.
去政府做事
But I persisted in serving in the police force.
但是我呢坚持要当警察
Because it is my dream
因为做警察
to become a policeman.
是我的一个梦想
Great!
好 不错啊
My name is Tian Dongbao.
我叫田冬宝
I did chicken raising in the countryside.
家里是在乡下养鸡
But my father didn't want me to do that.
我爹不让我养鸡
He told me a policeman would be paid more
他说当警察
than a chicken breeder.
比养鸡赚得多
Good.
好 那
You can breed some chickens
以后可以在所里
in our station house
养点儿鸡
to improve our food diversity.
改善一下伙食
And...
改
Yes, sir.
是
So the pretty girl.
这个小姑娘
Why do you serve in the police force?
为什么想当警察呀
Sir,
报告所长
I want to do the cause
我当警察
because I want to protect my family.
是因为想要保护家人
That sounds interesting.
这个说法很新鲜啊
You are Luo...
骆
Luo Minmin.
骆珉敏
Oh, yes.
对 对 对
I know you.
我知道你
You are the last one
考了最后一名
on the admission list.
那个小丫头
Don't feel embarrassed.
不要不好意思嘛
Their scores
这几个跟你差不多
are almost the same as yours.
八九不离十
It is so wonderful
难得来了一个
to have a policewoman here.
能拿得出手的
You don't need to do field operations
以后你就不用出警了
because that is a waste of your talent.
出警浪费粮食
When guests or superiors
上面要来个客人
visit the station house,
来个长官什么的
you are responsible for
你就负责端个茶
greeting
倒个水
and serving them.
迎来送往什么的
So that's it.
不用出警了
This young man
这个小伙子
has a good figure
这身材
and appearance.
这五官
Pretty good.
有卖相啊
What's it for to join the police force?
你为什么当警察呀
the Chairman said
蒋委员长说
police force must be the base of a country.
建国必先建警
A policeman must uphold justice
当警察是为了匡扶正义
and protect people.
保护百姓
[That bad man is a policeman.]
那个坏人他也是警察
[He wears a police cap and a uniform.]
戴了警帽 还穿了警服
Why do you take an English book with you?
出来旅行带本英文书啊
That tall man
那个个高的
is the guy in place of Bai's brother
就是顶替二白他弟弟
through a back-door dealing.
走后门那个
Let me introduce this man.
介绍一下啊
This is the captain of our station house.
这是咱们四所的
Chen Hao.
陈浩队长
He will be in charge of
你们以后具体的工作
your specific duties.
就由他负责
Say something.
讲两句
I need to get changed.
我先换个衣服去啊
We met before.
我们之前见过
Do you remember?
记得吗
Yes.
记得
What is your name?
叫什么名字
Xiang Yuansheng.
向远生
X-i-a-n-g Xiang?
方向的向
Y-u-a-n Yuan
任重道远的远
and s-h-e-n-g sheng.
生生不息的生
I'm your captain.
我是你们四所的队长
My name is Chen Hao.
我叫陈浩
You are going to
接下来你们将在四所
do a one-month-long internship.
进行一个月的实习
You will be divided into two groups.
两两开始分组
Two men in each group.
两人一组进行考核
If you pass the exam,
考试成绩合格
you will become a regular policeman.
转为正式警员
Otherwise, you will be fired.
不合格同时被辞退
Understand?
明白吗
Yes, sir.
明白
Now choose your partner.
现在分组
Captain.
队长
I want him with me in a group.
我想跟养鸡的一组
OK, approved.
好 那你俩一组
Sir.
报告队长
I have a request.
我有个申请
Speak.
说
I want to go on field operations with them.
我想和大家一样出警
Do you agree?
可以吗
Why did you say that?
谁不让你出警了
The inspector asked me
刚才所长要我在四所
to greet and serve guests
端茶倒水
and superiors.
迎来送往
No policewoman ever worked here
咱们四所之前
before.
一直没有女警
So it was awkward
抓女犯人
to arrest female criminals.
总是碍手碍脚的
You are the first one coming here.
现在好不容易来了一个
It will be such a waste
不让你出警
not letting you catch female criminals.
岂不是浪费粮食
Thank you, captain.
谢谢队长
Bai,
二白
show them around.
带他们介绍一下四所
OK.
好
Follow me.
跟我来
Come on.
来啊
Let me show you around.
给你们介绍介绍四所
[Although it is a small station,]
你别看咱们四所小
[it has a long history.]
但是历史比较悠久
[This way.]
这边
What happened to Xiang Yuansheng?
这个向远生是什么情况
He is a missing person.
他是失踪人口
He remains missing
失踪年限
for more than three years.
应该超过三年了
He has no immediate relatives in Shanghai.
在上海没有直系亲属
The landlord of the house he rented
租房的房东
is his only inheritor.
是他唯一的利益相关人
The court had approved
法院已经通过
the landlord's filing,
房东的申请
which means that man is dead.
宣告这人死亡了
So his household register card
所以他的户籍卡
and information in the
还有公安局户籍科
RRS of Public Security Bureau
里面的资料
need to be written off.
都需要被注销
I need this household register card
这张户籍卡
for a week.
我想借用一个星期
Then I will get rid of it.
之后我会把它销毁
No matter what happens,
不管发生任何事情
nobody will use it
这张户籍卡
again.
都不会再有人使用它
That room we visited just now
刚才那屋呢
is a resting room.
就是休息室
You can get changed there.
换衣服什么的就在那屋
Let me distribute your working areas.
我给你们分配一下座位
Chicken feeder
养鸡的
Restaurant boy.
开酒楼的
Here.
这儿
Yes, sir.
是
The tailender.
倒数第一
There.
那儿
Yes, sir.
是
You don't have to do this.
不用这样
What are you doing?
你干什么呢
I haven't given you a desk yet.
我给你安排座位了吗
The Chairman said
蒋委员长说
the police force is the base of a country.
建国必先建警
Did he call you
蒋委员长
last night?
晚上给你打电话说的
According to you, the status
按你这个说法
of the police is very important.
警察很重要啊
But why are we paid
那为什么我们工钱
so little?
那么少呢
Could you call
你能不能给蒋委员长
the Chairman
打个电话
to increase salaries for us?
给我们涨涨工钱
Some senior officers of the Police system
确实有警政官员提出
once provided a reform suggestion
将警政司
to turn the Police Department
升级为警政署的
into the Police Office.
改革方案
But it has been laid aside
只不过被一些政治原因
for some political reasons.
所搁置
Turning the department into the office
改司为署
means improving the status
也就是你说的
and welfare of the police,
提高警察地位和福利
Then your salary status will be improved.
也就是涨工资
Cut the crap
行 行 行
Don't tell me
你别跟我说这些
this nonsense.
没有用的
For some political reasons?
还政治原因
Do you even know politics?
你懂政治吗
OK.
来
Let me tell you what the politics is.
我告诉你什么叫政治
If I can't get the salary for June,
不给我发六月份的钱
don't expect me to investigate cases
就休想让我查
of July.
七月份的案
This is the politics.
这就叫政治
Do you understand?
明白了吗
Pour a mug of water for me.
给我倒杯水去
Here...
给
I'm talking to you.
我让你给我倒杯水去
Do you hear me?
听见了吗
Bai
二白
What are you doing?
干吗呢
Officer Xiang will be on alarm duty today.
今天接警由向警官负责
What?
他
Captain,
队长
Green hands never did that before
咱所没有新警员
here.
接警的先例
It's to test their capabilities.
正好看看新警员的能力
Luo Minmin.
骆珉敏
Yes, sir.
到
You go with him.
你跟他一块儿
You are partners.
你们是搭档
Help each other.
相互监督
Yes, sir.
是
Officer Luo.
骆警官
What day is it today?
请问今天周几
Let me check it out
这儿有报纸
from the newspaper.
我看看
Officer Luo.
骆警官
Do you get it?
看到了吗
Yes.
我看到了
See that.
你看
Two geese fought
这儿有两只鹅
and blocked the road.
在路上打架把路给堵了
Officer Xiang.
向警官
Did you ask me to do something
你刚才
just now?
是不是要问我什么问题
It's done.
没事儿
Thank you.
谢谢
Don't be shy.
你别不好意思说嘛
What is it?
什么事儿
The two geese...
这俩鹅
Where are you going?
着急忙慌干吗去啊
Will you come back for dinner?
回来吃饭不
No.
不回来
Captain Chen.
陈队长
I have checked the register book.
我查了我们的登记簿
I didn't get the name of Xiang Yuansheng.
没有这个叫向远生的
I'm certain
他肯定不是
he never checked into our hotel.
我们酒店的客人
Can you recall this man?
你看看照片有没有印象
No.
没有印象
Are you sure?
确定吗
Yes.
确定
Stop, the man in a suit.
穿西装那个
Do you live here?
你是这儿的房客吗
No.
不
I'm here to visit a friend.
我是来拜访朋友
Which room is your friend in?
你朋友住哪个屋
Who was in these rooms
那天这几间房
on that day?
都住了些什么人
that day.
都没有住人
As Mr. Meng checked in,
孟先生住进来的时候
he told us not to disturb him.
特意交代怕吵
So we kept those rooms
所以我们就
vacant.
没有安排住人
Thank you.
谢谢
It's hot.
小心烫啊
Sir.
组长
As I'm on a mission,
等我被正式启用那一天
will I get
会不会也给我
a code name?
一个代号啊
Just like yours
就像您的代号
which is 037.
零三七一样
Of course,
当然了
You are a good cop, Chen Hao.
你是个好警察 陈浩
Being a police officer is not only
警察对于你来讲
a camouflage
不仅仅是保护色
but also your dream.
也是你的梦想
I know
我知道
you are a man with an ideal.
你是个心中有梦的人
Have the noodles.
再不吃面就坨了啊
OK.
吃
Take your time.
小心烫啊
It is the record book of receiving alarms.
这是四所的接警记录
Note down those
今天下班之前
you recorded on it
把你们记的那些
before off-duty.
整理到这上面
Make clear notes about
什么人报的案
who called the police,
报的什么案
what kind of case,
接警人 出警人
and receiver and responder.
都记清楚了啊
May I ask
请问一下
if the record in recent days
这上面有这几天的
is on it?
接警记录吗
Captain Chen.
陈队长
Let me go.
你快撒开 撒开啊你
You are a scum.
真是个臭流氓
Captain Chen will put you
今天就让陈队
under arrest.
把你抓进去
Let go of me.
撒手 撒手
Get in.
你给我进去
Wait.
什么
You filthy bastard.
你这臭不要脸的耍流氓
I'm not.
谁 谁耍
Captain Chen is not here.
陈队长不在
You may tell me what happened to you.
有什么事情你可以找我
You are just a girl.
你一个女的
You can't deal with it.
你哪管得了这些啊
Wait...
不是
Officer.
这位警官 这位警官
Punish him.
警官
I'm innocent.
我冤枉的
He peeped at me while I was bathing.
他偷看我洗澡
[No. 031 is a girl abduction case.]
零三一 少女诱拐案
[No. 032 is a homicide case.]
零三二
[Both happened in the Wenhua Hotel.]
文华饭店凶杀案
[They both happened in the same place.]
地点都在文华饭店
[The responder was Chen Hao for both cases.]
接警的人都是陈浩
I can't deal with it. She can.
管不了 找她
Officer.
警官
Don't go.
你别走啊
Wait, Officer Xiang.
向警官 你别走啊
I can't handle it by myself.
我一个人处理不了
I'm the victim.
你来替我评评理
You bastard.
这臭流氓
Don't do it.
你别动手
Don't hit me.
打人是吧
Stop.
别动手
Stop it.
有话好好说
[No. 032:]
零三二
[The homicide in Wenhua Hotel.]
文华饭店凶杀案
[Three dead.]
三名死者
[They died of throat cut.]
割喉致死
[Meng Duoci disappeared.]
孟多慈失踪
[No. 031: Girl abduction.]
零三一 少女诱拐案
[Scene: Wenhua Hotel.]
地点文华饭店
Sorry.
对不起
He is the suspect.
嫌疑人竟然是他
So he was on the crime scene
所以他那天
that day.
也在凶案现场
Why are you in the archives room?
来档案室有事
I'm a freshman.
初来乍到
I'm here to read documents and
过来看看材料
learn the rules and regulations
了解一下警务的
of Police service.
规章制度
Report to me before stepping in the archive.
下次有事提前跟我报告
It's not a good idea to go in here without permission.
别随便进档案室
If my memory is good,
如果我没记错的话
in Wenhua Hotel,
你之前在文华饭店
you told me you came here for a journey.
说你是来旅游的
Yes.
对
You came to Shanghai for the first time?
第一次来上海
Had been before.
以前来过
But your ID card shows
可是你证件上写着
you are a native.
你是本地人
A native came here for a journey?
本地人来本地旅游
I lived with my family in another place.
这几年和家人住在外地
What is the place?
外地哪儿
Nanjing.
南京
It is a good city.
南京也是个不错的地方
Since you came here for a journey,
既然是来旅游
why are you serving in the police
怎么就突然
now?
当起警察来了
I heard
都说在上海当警察
the policemen here were paid well.
待遇不错
So I want to check it out.
想回来试试
You got ability
我看你的水平
more than trying your luck here.
不像是随便试试
You got full scores in two subject exams.
两门满分
If you were not absent from the last exam,
要不是缺考了最后一门
your score would get you
你的成绩都能
into the Police Department.
考去总局了
Why did you miss the exam?
怎么缺考了呢
I overslept.
睡觉睡过头
I missed that exam.
错过了
What a pity.
可惜了
What did you do before?
之前是做什么的
You checked my ID card.
证件你也看了
My information is written on it.
上面也写了
Fisherman.
渔民
Look at these hand cocoons.
这手茧
You did a lot of labor.
没少干活呀
They were rubbed by ropes.
缆绳磨手
You knew about the place.
四所的情况你也看见了
If you got powerful connections,
既然是托关系进来的
I advise you
我建议你
to select
可以选择一个
a better place.
更好的地方
This place
这个地方
is good enough for me.
就很好
Great.
挺好就好
This is your ID card.
登记完了 还给你
It's not yours, right?
这证件不是你的吧
What are you talking about?
我听不懂你在说什么
Does it have any problem?
这个证件有什么问题吗
No.
没什么问题
Xiang Yuansheng.
向远生
It is a good name.
名字不错
Thank you.
谢谢
I need to go back to my duty.
我回接警处了
I told you already.
我告诉你了
You bitch.
这臭娘们儿
Don't hit her.
不能动手
You set me up.
我叫你冤枉我
This is the police station.
这里是警察所
You bitch.
你这个臭娘们儿
Let her go.
松开
Do you want to try again?
还打吗
This bitch framed me.
这臭娘们儿冤枉我
I won't.
不 不打了
Get out of here.
走
OK.
好
Thank you, officer.
谢谢警官
Next time,
你下次再遇到什么事情
don't use violence.
你就别动手
So...
这 这
What is the office's name?
这个警官怎么称呼啊
Officer Xiang.
向警官
Goodbye, Officer Xiang.
向警官再见
Zuo.
老左
Who is behind him?
他是走谁的后门进来的
Do you mean Xiang Yuansheng?
向
You didn't know anything.
你怎么什么都不知道啊
I asked.
我问过
But it looked weird.
神神秘秘的
Nobody told me.
谁也不告诉我
But you have reminded me.
你这么一提醒我
I often heard rustlings
我说最近这院子里面
in the yard.
窸窸窣窣
Is there a rat in the house?
闹耗子呢
Can you get a cat?
有猫没有
Get one for me.
给我领一只来
Cats always come after rats.
有耗子才有猫
What do you mean?
啥意思啊
Just keep him.
留身边呗
Let's observe what he attempts to do.
看他想干吗
What?
留在身边
Rats are rats.
这耗子能有什么目的
They feed on birds.
想吃我鸟呗
Why are you laughing?
你还乐上了你
Have some more.
多吃点儿
You have a big appetite.
还挺能吃
Here.
来
Thank you.
谢谢二白哥
Have more.
来 多吃点儿
You don't have to thank me.
不用谢我
It's quite normal
第一天当警察
on your first day.
手忙脚乱很正常
Actually,
其实
I want to ask you a question.
我是想问一下
Did I look embarrassed
刚才
just now?
我的样子很丢人吗
What?
什么
I know
我知道我那个样子
I damaged the image of the police force.
肯定会有损警察形象
I was at the bottom
我考进来的时候
of the admission list,
就是最后一名
narrowly made it.
多一分都没有
If someone was weeded out,
要是淘汰一个人的话
it would be me.
肯定会淘汰我的
But I'm determined to
但是我一定要
stay here.
留在这里当警察
Therefore,
所以
from now on,
从今往后的日子
I wish
我希望
we could help each other.
我们能互相帮助
So
这样吧
allow me to introduce myself
我给你
to you.
正式介绍一下我自己
My name is Luo Minmin.
我叫骆珉敏
If you get in trouble
你以后要是
in future,
遇到什么事情
I can help you.
都可以找我帮忙
I heard
听说
you are the one getting the job through back-door dealings,
你就是开后门进来那个
right?
对吧
Yes.
算是吧
You surely
那你肯定能
understand my feeling,
理解我的感受
right?
对吧
So let's call it a deal.
那就这么说定了
Thank you for helping me out.
谢谢你刚才帮我解围
We are partners,
我们俩还是搭档呢
right?
对吧
If possible,
如果有可能
I advise you
我建议你
to change a partner as soon as possible!
尽快换一个搭档
I don't get it.
什么人哪
What a strange man!
奇奇怪怪的